VINICIUS GIL

E-mail: viniciusgil_es@hotmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/viniciusgil88/ https://viniciusgil.github.io/portfoliolive/ Liverpool UK – Open to relocation

PROFILE

I am a passionate gamer, and I have a deep understanding of the gaming industry. I am also familiar with the latest gaming trends and technologies. I am confident that I can use my skills and experience to help your company create high-quality games that players will love

As an individual I am resilient, dedicated, professional, a great communicator and have strong attention to detail which are keys skills I can bring from working in the demanding hospitality sector.

I am able to get on with the job with the minimal amount of supervision. I am always willing to get involved in a variety of tasks to help out where I can. I am eager to learn new things, and I am always looking for ways to improve my skills. I am also a quick learner, and I am confident that I can quickly adapt to your company's culture and procedures.

Tech skills

∠ C#

✓ Jira

✓ HTML

✓ TestRail

✔ GitHub

✓ XLOC

Microsoft Office

✓ Unreal

✓ QA

Soft skills

✔ Positive

Multi-tasking

Punctuality

✓ Eye for detail

✓ Team work

✓ Empath

Adaptability

✔ Patient

Communication

Career summary

11/2023 - Present

Universally Speaking

Localisation Quality Assurance Technician - LQA

- ✓ Verified in-game text for linguistic accuracy, addressing errors and ensuring cosmetic integrity.
- ✓ Maintained contextual consistency, assessed cultural appropriateness, and validated localized text implementation.
- ✓ Conducted functional localization testing, ensuring seamless gameplay across all languages.

- ✓ Identified and documented bugs, improving overall game quality through test-case execution.
- ✓ Adhered to processes, providing occasional in-house translations and actively participating in team meetings.
- ✓ Delivered daily status reports, supported the lead in side tasks, and mentored new team members.

06/2023 - 11/2023

<u>PlaytestCloud</u>

Play Tester(Gaming) - Freelance

- ✓ Provided feedback for mobile games during prototyping, development, soft launch, and after release.
- ✓ Suggest changes and corrections to developers for optimal.

05/ 2023 - 05/2023

<u>Gigacycle</u>

IT Technician

- ✓ Formatting and test Desktop, laptops, tablets and servers.
- ✓ Repairing or replacing damaged hardware.
- ✓ Perform tests and evaluations.

10/2022 - 02/2023

Aramco

VR Commercial Project – Hinkah

In my role as a junior game developer, I had the chance to work on a VR commercial project with a client provided by a game development boot camp course. Using the Unity Engine, I was able to create a prototype of Soft Skills training which was presented to hundreds of investors in Saudi Arabia.

On the coding side, I wrote scripts for the game prototype in C#, and developed UI elements, for the buttons I added audio and functionalities, for all conversations for both languages (English and Arabic), and audio too, for every text and audio, I had to implement localization. The hands interactions with the UI and scenes, teleportation, etc... Make the 3D animations work in the scenes.

The client requested a system of answers like a quiz, with specification points for the correct answers.

I also served as the communication leader, managing the expectations of the client, keeping them informed on our progress, and scheduling meetings. This was a valuable experience that allowed me to further develop my skills in game development and gain a better understanding of the industry.

Furthermore, I took the initiative to learn new technologies and techniques to improve the game's design and keep up with industry standards.

Evelyn's Cafe Bar LTD- Manchester, UK Head Chef/Sous Chef I have worked in a range of different restaurants such as a Primary School.

- ✓ Navarro Lounge, Manchester, UK.
- ✓ Racconto Lounge, Bury, Manchester, UK.
- ✓ St Mary's RC Primary School Swinton, Manchester, UK.
- ✓ Patisserie Valerie Deansgate, Greater Manchester, UK.

2006-2011 Football Player

My career journey as a professional football player started age 8, with training three times per week. By the age of 10 I was getting three buses on my own, to travel 1.45 hours to training sessions. At age 14 I left home to train in another state, sharing a room with 21 other boys. During this time I travelled all over Brazil and became a professional player aged 18. Throughout my career I was usually chosen to be a captain of the team because of my leadership skills.

- ✓ Nouvo Mazzolada, Italy.
- ✓ Mogliano Calcio, Italy.
- √Vitória FC, Brazil.

Voluntary Experience

- ✓ World Youth Day, 07/2013
- ✓ Orphanage, Fundação Fé e Alegria OMG, 07/2012 04/2014

Languages

- ✓ English Fluent
- √ Brazilian Portuguese Native
- ✓ Italian Fluent

Education

- ✓ Bury College English Skills Speaking and listening Entry 3 2019 -2020
- ✓ Estácio de Sá University International Commerce Degree 2012 2014
- √ Casa Verde Computer Maintenance Course (6 months) 2007
- √ High School Finals (A level equivalent) State Of Espirito Santo Government
- √'EEEF. Maria Ericina Santos' 2003 -2006.